▍2026 美网 女单半决赛
莱巴金娜 3-6 6-4 6-4 高芙 · 赛后场上采访
Elena,
埃琳娜
what an incredible match you just played
你刚打了一场了不起的比赛
to send yourself to your first US Open final.
把自己送进了首个美网决赛
After the first set,
输掉首盘之后
how were you able to reset and come out
你是怎么重整旗鼓
and play such good tennis in the second
在第二盘和第三盘
and third?
打出这么好的网球的？
I feel like first set it was still a good start,
我觉得首盘开局其实不错
you know, it was just one break
只是被破了一个发球局
and of course there is nerves.
当然也会紧张
Koko, she is a great player.
高芙是很出色的球员
It's always tough to play against her.
跟她打总是很难
Even
就算
if sometimes her first serve doesn't go,
有时候她一发进不去
the second one is so heavy
二发也非常有力量
that it's difficult to dictate the rallies.
很难主导回合
And yeah, I just took a deep breath,
我就是深吸了一口气
you know, was trying to talk positive
试着跟自己说些正面的话
with myself and just told myself that I need
然后告诉自己
to fight and try to show good tennis.
必须去拼 打出好网球
In the third, you served for the match,
第三盘你有一个发球胜赛局
got broken, and came back
被破了 然后你又回来
and played an incredible return game.
打了一个精彩的接发球局
Did you lose any confidence at 5-3
5-3的时候你动摇过吗
or were you still pretty confident
还是一直都有信心
at your abilities to return at 5-4?
5-4时能破掉她的发球？
It was such a close set
那一盘太接近了
and I feel like I got a little bit lucky
我觉得自己有点运气
on this
就那么一下
on her serve couple deep returns,
她的发球局 几个很深的回球
one mistake from her.
她出现一次失误
It went quickly my way
局面很快就转向我这边
and then I know you guys wanted Koko
我知道你们都想让高芙
to win and I think it
赢下这场球
was a real battle and
我觉得那是一场真正的苦战
as I said few moments really it went my way
就像我说的 几个瞬间倒向了我
and in the end I mean I was just trying
最后我只是努力
to still be focused try to stay aggressive
保持专注 保持侵略性
and somehow won the match.
然后就这么赢下了比赛
Well well great job in winning the match.
祝贺你赢下这场比赛
In the final,
决赛里
you will face a familiar opponent
你会遇到一位熟悉的对手
in a Grand Slam final in Aryna Sabalenka.
大满贯决赛的对手萨巴伦卡
What are your thoughts
你怎么看
on that upcoming incredible women's final?
即将到来的这场女单决赛？
Well,
这个嘛
she's I mean she's unbelievable player
她是难以置信的球员
and she was playing really well today,
今天她打得非常好
I feel like.
我是这么觉得的
And I definitely need to step
我肯定需要
my game up serve much better,
把状态提上去 发球要好得多
start to serve much better than today
要比今天发得好得多
and stay aggressive go for the shots
保持侵略性 去搏那些球
because I know whenever you get
因为我知道 只要有机会
opportunity you need to really go
你就必须真的去搏
for your shots especially
去搏你的球 特别是
with Aryna.
面对萨巴伦卡的时候
So yeah just try to enjoy.
所以就是试着去享受
I think I did maximum on this tournament
我觉得这站我已经做到极限了
already especially doubting
特别是之前还怀疑
if I'm going to be able to play here.
自己能不能来这儿打
So yeah, I just tried to enjoy.
所以我就是试着享受